让我们回顾一下我们在解决反向运动学问题方面所学到的东西
Let's recap what we've learnt about solving the inverse Kinematic problem for particular
机器人手臂。到目前为止，我们已经查看了分析解决方案，这涉及到我们创建模型
robot arms. So far we've looked at the analytic solution and that involved us creating a model
机器人的关节和链接。我们写下正向运动学的方程式
of the robot's joints and links. We write down the equations for the forward kinematics
机器人手臂，这是一个相对简单的事情。
of the robot arm and that's relatively a straightforward thing to do.
接下来是困难的部分，我们需要写下很多方程式
Next comes the hard part, where we need to write down a lot of equations in attempt to
解决未知的关节变量，这需要一些人类的洞察力。经常在
solve for the unknown joint variables and that requires some human insight. Often when
你试图做到这一点，你会发现自己在你来之前要去一些盲道
you're trying to do this, you'll find yourself going down some blind alleys before you come
退出并确定获得解决方案的正确方法。
back out and determine the right way to get to the solution.
这个过程可以使用计算机代数包自动化;你可以编写那些软件
This process can be automated, using a computer algebra package; you can write software that
将解决某类机器人手臂的逆运动学问题。最大的优势
will solve the inverse kinematics for certain classes of robot arms. The great advantage
解析解决方案是它明确地显示了多个配置
of the analytic solution is that it explicitly shows the multiple configurations that the
机器人手臂可以进入。所以对于我们的两个链接机械手，我们展示了两个中间配置
robot arm can be in. So for our two link manipulator, we showed two configurations with the middle
接头位于对角​​线下方或对角线上方。
joint either below the diagonal line or above the diagonal line.
对于Puma560机器人，我们展示了配置，就像左撇子或者左撇子一样
For the Puma 560 robot, we showed configurations where it's like a left handed person or a
右撇子等等。当您使用时，会明确地显示多种配置
right handed person and so on. The multiple configurations come out explicitly when you
解决分析方程。
solve the analytic equations.
分析解决方案的另一个优点是你最终为表达式编写表达式
Another advantage of the analytic solution is you end up writing expressions for the
关于末端执行器姿势的关节角度，它们非常紧凑，这意味着
joint angles in terms of the end effector pose and they are quite compact and that means
它们执行起来非常快。
that they are very fast to execute.
随着机器人中关节数量的增加，问题变得越来越困难。
The problem becomes increasingly difficult as the number of joints in the robot increases.
在前面的部分中，我们得到了一个简单的两个关节机器人的解决方案
In an earlier section we derived the solution for a simple two joint robot and already that
花了很多幻灯片来提出解决方案。什么来到我们的
took quite a number of slides in order to come up with the solution. What comes to our
救援是几十年来，聪明的人已经确定了反向运动解决方案
rescue is that over many decades, smart people have determined the inverse kinematic solutions
对于特定的机器人或特定类型的机器人，所以他们已经完成了艰苦的工作
for particular robots or for particular classes of robots, so they've done the hard work of
得出解决方案，这些已发表在文献中。
deriving the solutions and these have been published in the literature.
因此，如果你有一个特定的机器人，并且你正在寻找一个解决方案，那就去吧
So if you've got a particular robot and you're looking for a solution, go and hit up the
文献，看看有人已经为你解决了这个问题。
literature and see if somebody has already solved this problem for you.
当您尝试确定六自由度机器人的逆运动学时，
When you're trying to determine the inverse kinematics for a six degree of freedom robot,
拥有所谓的“球形手腕”真的非常有用。现在是一个球形
it's really, really useful to have what's called a "Spherical Wrist." Now a spherical
如图所示，腕部是三个腕关节轴都在公共点相交的腕部
wrist is one in which the three wrist joint axes all intersect at a common point, as shown
在这个草图这里。几乎所有工业机器人都有球形手腕。真是太棒了
in this sketch here. Almost all industrial robots have a spherical wrist. It's quite
一个复杂的机制，但它确实很简单，当涉及到确定
a complex mechanism but it leads to great simplicity when it comes to determining the
机器人的反向运动学。
inverse kinematics of the robot.
事实上，它的作用是让我们将问题分成两部分。它允许我们解决
In fact what it does is allow us to partition the problem into two. It allows us to solve
对于机器人的末端执行器的位置，XYZ坐标然后分开
for the position of the robot’s end effector, the XYZ co-ordinate and then separately to
求解机器人末端执行器的方向，即可以的方向
solve for the orientation of the robot's end effector, that is the orientation that could
用滚动，俯仰，偏航角或欧拉角表示。但是会发生什么
be expressed in terms roll, pitch, yaw angles or in terms of Euler angles. But what happens
如果无法确定分析解决方案？
if it's not possible to determine the analytic solution?
也许机器人没有球形手腕，或者如果它太难以计算
Perhaps the robot doesn't have a spherical wrist or what if it's just too hard to figure
out或者你不能费心去完成需要确定的代数页面
out or you can't be bothered to go through the pages of algebra required to determine
解决方案？那么有一个替代方案，那就是找到一个数值解决方案
the solution? Well there is an alternative and that is to find a numerical solution to
问题。我们总能确定机器人的前向运动学，这是相对直的
the problem. We can always determine the forward kinematics of a robot, that's relatively straight
正如我们在前一讲中所展示的那样前进。如果我们知道我们想要的姿势
forward to do as we showed in the previous lecture. If we know the desired pose of our
机器人，我将称之为Ksi星，然后我们所要做的就是调整关节角度
robot, which I'm going to call Ksi star, then all we have to do is adjust the joint angles
直到前向运动学给出给我们的姿势Ksi等于期望值Ksi
until the pose given to us by the forward kinematics Ksi equals the desired value Ksi
星。所以你可以把它想象成拥有大量的表盘，每个表盘
star. So you could think of it perhaps as having a large number of dials, each dial
代表一个特定的关节角度，我只是调整所有这些表盘，直到
represents a particular joint angle and I’m just going to adjust all of those dials until
机器人的末端效应器姿势等于我想要的姿势。一种更正式的描述方式
the robot's end effector pose equals the pose that I want. A more formal way of describing
像这样的问题是将其表示为优化问题。
a problem like this is to represent it as an optimization problem.
我想要做的是最小化正向运动学给出的相对姿势
What I want to do is minimize the relative pose which is given by the forward kinematics
机器人与所需姿势的倒数复合，我想知道关节
of the robot compounded with the inverse of the desired pose and I want to know the joint
导致这种最小化的角度。
angles that cause this minimum.
我们主要讨论串联机器人，这些机器人是由一系列机器人组成的
We've mostly talked about serial linked robots and these are robots formed by a chain of
链接，从机器人的基础开始，我们有一个链接，该链接支撑第二个
links, starting at the base of the robot we have a link, that link holds up the second
链接，它保持第三个链接等等。
link, which holds up the third link and so on.
机器人的另一种结构是所谓的并联机器人，如图所示
An alternative structure for a robot is what's called a parallel link robot and that's shown
在右边。它们的优点是所有电机都放在底座中。
here on the right. They have the advantage that all the motors are placed in the base.
这比串行链路机器人更有优势，其中每个电机不仅要支撑它
This has advantages over a serial link robot where each motor has to hold up not only the
下一个链接，但也驱动链接超出该链接。
next link but also the motor that drives the link beyond that.
平行连杆机器人也非常非常隆起，它们能够进行非常高速的运动。
Parallel link robots are also very, very ridged and they're capable of very high speed motion.
它们用于高速，非常精确的拾取和放置操作。所以对于一个序列
They're used for high speed, very precise, pick and place operations. So for a serial
链接机器人，运动学-正向运动学很容易确定，非常容易编写
link robot, the kinematics - the forward kinematics is very easy to determine, very easy to write
下。然而，对于并联机器人，正向运动学非常非常复杂
down. However for a parallel link robot, the forward kinematics is very, very complex and
甚至可能不存在分析形式。对于串行链接机器人，反向运动学
an analytical form may not even exist. For a serial link robot, the inverse kinematics
通常是复杂的，可能不存在分析形式。但对于大多数并行链接
is typically complex and analytic form may not exist. However for most parallel link
机器人，反向运动学实际上很容易确定和分析形式
robots, the inverse kinematics is actually very easy to determine and an analytic form
永远存在。因此串行和并行链接机器人之间存在一些互补性;一
always exists. So there is some complementarity between serial and parallel link robots; one
有一个简单的正向运动学，另一个有一个简单的反向运动学。
has an easy forward kinematics, the other has an easy inverse kinematics.